# **BILLY GIGURTSIS**



### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Highly effective and well-rounded Information Technology professional with deep-dive experience in both technical support and information security, including security analysis. Selected out of thousands of applicants to attend the 10-week 2022 SANS / HM Government "<u>Upskill in Cyber</u>" program. Known for delivering excellent service in fast-paced environments, with the skillset to analyze and act on complex information. Outstanding communicator with extensive experience collaborating with high performing teams to ensure service delivery.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Risk Management
- Documentation & Reporting
- Security Analysis
- Triaging & Prioritization

- Incident Response
- Phishing Analysis

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PING IDENTITY, LONDON, ENGLAND, MARCH 2021 — PRESENT

#### **DESKTOP SUPPORT ENGINEER**

- Execute strategic analysis & incident response to security alerts entering the helpdesk, collaborating with the
  infrastructure security team to ensure integrity of our systems, using software such as Splunk, Sophos, and
  Microsoft Sentinel.
- Align objectives and bridge communication between the IT support and security team to maintain a strong security posture while following ITIL.
- Resolved over 1400 tickets originating from a global, 1300+ userbase within my first 10 months of employment while being the sole Desktop Support Engineer in EMEA.
- Review and solve issues with hardware and software including macOS, Zoom, SSO/MFA, M365, Azure and more.

HISTORIC ROYAL PALACES, LONDON, ENGLAND, MARCH 2020 — MAY 2020

#### **CONTRACT SERVICE DESK ANALYST**

- Served as the primary point of contact for over 1200 users facing technical issues in multiple UK Palaces.
- Communicated with users to identify and investigate issues, implementing effective solutions to restore full functionality while following ITIL.
- Coordinated with third-party vendors for repairs.
- Investigated incoming security alerts, triaging and forwarding cases to the network/security team.
- Educated users in common troubleshooting steps and taught best security practices when it was appropriate.

Brentside High School, December 2019 — January 2020

#### **CONTRACT IT TECHNICIAN**

- Monitored and addressed incoming tickets for the school's service desk accessible to over 1500 students.
- Consolidated the number of complex tickets from over 100 to less than 20 in under a month as the sole service desk agent by analyzing and prioritizing with maximum efficiency.
- Administered the school's Active Directory & Windows Server 2016, including resetting passwords and onboarding employees.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

CompTIA Security+, May 2022

SANS GIAC Foundational Cybersecurity Technologies (GFACT), August 2022 SANS training for GIAC Security Essentials (GSEC) exam, to be certified September 2022 BILLY GIGURTSIS Page 2

## **PROJECTS / TRAINING**

#### **PROJECTS**

Created a home lab for learning security analysis/virtual networking. Includes seven virtual machines
(Splunk, Kali, pfSense, Security Onion and more) spun up and networked within VMware Workstation. More
information can be found on my blog: <a href="https://www.bgigurtsis.com/2022/08/sechomelab.html">https://www.bgigurtsis.com/2022/08/sechomelab.html</a>

 Built my blog from the ground up using static site generator Jekyll as the foundation. My codebase is on GitHub, with the site hosted and CI/CD implemented through AWS. Blog link: <a href="https://www.bgigurtsis.com/">https://www.bgigurtsis.com/</a>

#### **TRAINING**

- SANS SEC275: Foundations Computers, Technology, & Security.
- SANS SEC401: Security Essentials: Network, Endpoint, and Cloud.
- Blue Team Level 1 Security Operations labs/training including: Phishing Analysis, Threat Intelligence, Digital Forensics, SIEM usage, and Incident Response.
- Red Hat Linux Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) Complete Video Course by Sanders Van Vugt.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **UPSKILL IN CYBER, 2022**

SANS / HM Government

10-Week course to rapidly reskill individuals for roles in cyber security. Included two GIAC certifications with SANS training, developing both soft and technical skills

### VOLUNTEERING

CODERDOJO, LONDON, ENGLAND, JANUARY 2020 — JUNE 2021

#### **MENTOR**

- Helped children to learn Scratch/Python, encouraging them to search for solutions.
- Guide and encourage children by facilitating their project work, as opposed to conventionally teaching them.
- Showcasing and celebrating their work at the end of the session.

MARIE CURIE HOSPICE UK, LONDON, ENGLAND, MARCH 2017 — JUNE 2020

#### **HELPER/BEFRIENDER**

- Connected with and befriended individuals with terminal illnesses in their own homes.
- Assisted individuals with daily living activities such as making tea or shopping.
- Leveraged active listening skills to provide person-centered style support to service users.

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**Interests:** Operational technology security (SCADA/ICS), security architecture, functional programming (Clojure), Arduino, and low-level computing/reverse engineering. Posts about these interests and others can be found <u>on my blog</u>.